Los Angeles, CA, USA +1 (919) 904-2124 dmytro.karataiev@gmail.com

Dmytro Karataiev

adkdevelopment.com github.com/dmytroKarataiev linkedin.com/in/dmytrokarataiev

Summary:

Senior Android developer with portfolio of open-source applications published on Google Play and interested in the field of Machine Learning, who believes in test-driven development and Clean approach to coding. Also have extensive experience in marketing, including successful portfolio management and new brands launches.

Technical Skills

Languages: Java, Python.

Android: Dagger 2, RxJava 2, MVP, TDD.

Databases/Other: Realm, SQLite, Git, Gradle, CI services.

Exposed to: Kotlin, JavaScript, PHP, CSS3.

Work Experience

F3 Software – Senior Android Developer

Los Angeles, USA | October 2016 – Present

- Leading a team of developers to continuously deliver, improve and extend a series of applications.
- Working closely with UI designers, business analysts and testers in a highly collaborative environment.
- Developing the architecture of apps and maintaining high crash free user percentage (>95%).

Freelance – Android Developer

Los Angeles, USA | August 2014 – September 2016

- Developed Android applications for clients according to their requirements.
- Worked under NDA on one big health-related project and as a tester for an Android MOOC platform.

Yalantis - Android Intern - GitHub Page

Dnipro, Ukraine | February 2016 - June 2016

- Created three Android applications with an increasing level of complexity.
- Used technologies: MVP Architecture, RxJava, Retrofit, Facebook API, Dagger 2, etc.

DANONE Nutricia – Marketing, Strategy and Insights Manager

Kyiv, Ukraine | April 2013 - August 2014

Managed portfolio of 3 brands, achieved 2nd position in the Value Market Share (+700bps Year on Year).

Unilever – Brand Manager

Kyiv, Ukraine | July 2010 – April 2013

Achieved 1st place in Volume/Value Market Shares (+1000bps), launched new brand, 40 additional SKU's.

Project Experience

Machine Learning Nanodegree projects - GitHub Page

June 2016 - November 2016

• Completed projects on Supervised (Boston Housing Prices, Student Intervention System), Unsupervised (Creating Customer Segments) and Reinforcement learning (Smartcab).

Earthquake Survival - GitHub Page - Google Play

April 2016 - Present

- Earthquake monitoring application with survival information, notifications, auto syncs.
- Uses SyncAdapter, ContentProvider, Loaders, Maps, Locations, Geofences, Notifications, RxJava, Retrofit.

The Movie Database - GitHub Page - Google Play

December 2015 - Present

- Fast and efficient client to The Movie Database with Search and Favorites functionality and tablet design.
- Uses ContentProvider, YouTube API, RxJava, Retrofit.

BBC News Reader - GitHub Page - Google Play

August 2016

- RSS news reader for the BBC XML feed.
- Uses MVP Architecture, Realm database, JobScheduler, RxJava, Retrofit.

Morse Flashlight - GitHub Page - Google Play

January 2016

- Flashlight application with simple design, fast speed, Morse code and an Emergency Signal.
- Works as Service with all the tasks on background thread (Service, Camera2 API).

Education

Udacity – Machine Learning Engineer Nanodegree - Verified certificateNovember 2016Udacity – Android Developer Nanodegree - Verified certificateApril 2016Taurida National University, Simferopol, Ukraine – Political Science, M.A., GPA 3.57June 2010

Certificates

edX MIT – 6.005.1-2x, Advanced Software construction in Java	September 2016 – April 2017
Coursera University of Michigan – Programming in Python (4 courses)	October 2015 – March 2016
Coursera Stanford – Algorithms and Analysis (Part 1)	October 2015 – December 2015
edX MIT – 6.00.1x, 6.00.2x Computer Science and Python Programming	August 2015 – December 2015

Honors and Activities

Udacity Transcend Award

Chaire of the warr award for the host brand in the market (2011, 201

June 2016

Choice of the year award for the best brand in the market (2011, 2012)

December 2011, December 2012

First prize and diploma for the best paper – Moscow State University International Conference

April 2010